Onward, Ohauncey!
冲啊，嫱嬉
To the highest room of the tallest tower...
向高塔顶端的房间冲啊
...where my princess awaits rescue from her handsome Prince Oharming!
那儿我的公主正等待着 她英俊的查明王子来救她
This is worse than "Love Letters". I hate dinner theater!
这比《情书》还难看 我讨厌晚餐剧场
Me, too.
我也是
Whoa there, Ohauncey!
就这里，嫱嬉
Hark! The brave Prince Oharming approacheth.
听！勇敢的查明王子来了
Fear not, fair maiden. I shall slay the monster that guards you...
不要怕，美女 我会杀死那个怪物
...then take my place as rightful king.
然后正当的坐上王位
What did she say?
她说什么？
It's Shrek!
是史莱克！
Whoo, Shrek, yeah!
史莱克，耶！
Prepare, foul beast...
受死吧，恶心的怪物
...to enter into a world of pain with which you are not familiar!
送你去一个你从没感受过的痛苦世界
Happy birthday to thee Happy birthday to thee
祝你生日快乐 祝你生日快乐
Do you mind?
你介意吗？
Do you mind? Boring!
你介意吗？无聊！
Prepare, foul beast...
受死吧，恶心的怪物
Someday you'll be sorry.
总有一天你会后悔的
We already are!
我们已经后悔了！
Mommy...
妈咪
You're right. I can't let this happen.
你是对的，我不能让这发生
I can't!
绝不
I am the rightful King of Far Far Away.
我才是遥远国正当的国王
And I promise you this, Mother...
我向你保证，母亲…
...I will restore dignity to my throne.
我会恢复我王座的尊严
And this time,
这一次
no one will stand in my way.
没人能够阻止我
Good morning.
早上好
Morning breath.
早晨的呼吸
I know. Isn't it wonderful?
我知道，多美妙啊
Good morning, good morning
早上好，早上好
The sun is shining through
太阳照屁屁啦
Good morning, good morning To you
早上好，你也早上好
And you! And you!
还有你！ 你！
They grow up so fast.
他们长得真快啊
Not fast enough.
还不够快
You'll be filling in for the King and Queen.
你们将即位国王和王后
Several functions require your attendance, sir.
有几个场合需要你出席，殿下
Great! Let's get started.
太好了！我们开始吧
Oome on, lazybones. Time to get moving!
拜托，懒骨头 该行动了！
You need to get a pair ofjammies.
你真的需要一套睡衣裤
《怪物史瑞克3》
∮ I got some sleep and I needed it ∮
∮ 我睡了一会儿，我需要它 ∮
∮ Not a lot, just a little bit ∮
∮ 不是很多，只是一点点 ∮
∮ Someone's always trying to keep me from it ∮
∮ 总有人想阻止我 ∮
∮ It's a crying shame ∮
∮ 真丢脸 ∮
∮ It's a royal pain in the neck ∮
∮ 这是一种皇家的痛苦 ∮
I knight thee.
我封你为爵士
If you're filling in for a king, you should look like one.
如果你想继任国王 你就该表现的像个国王
Oan somebody come in and work on Shrek?
谁能进来帮史莱克弄一下造型？
I will see what I can do.
我看看我能怎么做
Yeah, wow.
耶，哇
Is this really necessary?
这真的有必要吗？
Quite necessary, Fiona.
当然有必要，菲奥娜
- I'm Shrek, you twit. - Whatever.
- 我是史莱克，你个笨蛋 - 管他呢
This isn't a rehearsal, peoples. Let's see some hustle!
好，这不是排练 我们来看看下面的骚动吧
Smiles, everyone! Smiles!
微笑，各位！微笑！
I don't know how much longer I can keep this up.
我不知道我还能忍多久
I'm sorry, but can you just try to grin and bear it?
对不起，但你能不能只是露齿一笑 再忍耐一下呢？
It's just until Dad gets better.
等到爸爸好转就没事了
Shrek?
史莱克？
You look handsome.
你看上去很英俊
Oome here, you.
过来，你
My butt is itching up a storm and I can't reach it in this monkey suit.
我屁股痒的要命 穿了这猴子装我够不到
Hey, you! Oome here. What's your name?
嘿，你！过来，你叫什么名字？
Fiddlesworth, sir.
费斗斯沃斯，殿下
Perfect.
好极了
Ladies and gentlemen...
女士们先生们…
...Princess Fiona and Sir Shrek!
有请菲奥娜公主和史莱克殿下
Ahh! You've got it.
啊！就是那里
A little to the left.
再左边一点
That's it! That's good.
就是那里，很好
Oh, yeah! Scratch that thing! You're on it.
哦，耶，挠，就是那个
Shrek!
史莱克！
My eye!
我的眼睛！
What are you doing?
你在干吗？
Fiona!
菲奥娜！
- Are you okay? - Yeah. I'm fine.
- 你还好吗？ - 嗯，我很好
Shrimp! My favorite!
哦，虾，我的最爱
- That's it! We're leaving! - Oalm down.
- 我受够了，我们走！ - 冷静
Oalm down? Who do you think we're kidding? I am an ogre.
冷静？你认为我们是在跟谁开玩笑？ 我是个怪物
I'm not cut out for this, Fiona, and I never will be.
我不适合做这个，菲奥娜 永远都不适合
I think that went well.
我认为会好的
Donkey!
驴子！
Oome on, Shrek!
别这样，史莱克！
Some people just don't understand boundaries.
有些人就是不识相
Just think. A couple more days and we'll be back home...
想想，再过几天我们就能回家去了
...in our vermin-filled shack strewn with fungus...
回到我们那点缀着菌菇 充满着虫子的小木屋了
...and filled with the stench of mud and neglect.
充满着泥土的气息和懒散
You had me at "vermin-filled".
你让我好像回到了那里
And, um... maybe even the pitter-patter of little feet on the floor.
也许地上还有一串小脚印
That's right, the swamp rats will be spawning.
对，沼泽里的老鼠开始产卵
Uh, no.
不
What I'm thinking of is a little bigger than a swamp rat.
我想到的是比沼泽鼠更大一点的
Donkey?
驴子？
No, Shrek. What if, theoretically...
不，史莱克，假设，理论上的…
...they were little ogre feet?
是小怪物的小脚印？
Honey, let's be rational about this.
亲爱的，我们要理智对待这个事情
Have you seen a baby lately?
你最近看到过婴儿吗？
They just eat and poop, and they cry...
他们只会吃然后拉，还有哭
...then they cry when they poop and poop when they cry.
当他们拉的时候哭 哭的时候拉
Now, imagine an ogre baby.
现在，想像一下怪物婴儿
They extra-cry and they extra-poop.
他们哭的更厉害，拉的也更厉害
Shrek, don't you ever think about having a family?
史莱克，你从没想过拥有一个家庭吗？
Right now, you're my family.
现在，你就是我的家庭
Somebody better be dying.
那么急干吗，有人要死了吗
I'm dying.
我快要死了
Harold?
哈罗德？
Don't forget to pay the gardener, Lillian.
不要忘了付钱给园丁，莉莉安
Of course, darling.
当然，亲爱的
Fiona.
菲奥娜
Yes, Daddy?
在，爸爸？
I know I made many mistakes with you.
我知道我过去错怪了你很多
It's okay.
没事的
But your love for Shrek has...
但你对史莱克的爱…
...taught me much.
教会了我很多
My dear boy...
我亲爱的孩子…
...I am proud to call you my son.
我很自豪称你为我的儿子
And I'm proud to call you my frog...
我也很自豪称你为我的青蛙…
...King dad-in-law.
…国王岳父
Now there is a matter of business to attend to.
现在有件事要处理
The Frog King... is dead.
青蛙国王…死了
Put your hat back on, fool.
戴好你的帽子，傻瓜
Shrek...
史莱克…
...please come hither.
请来这边
Yeah, Dad?
是的，爸爸？
This kingdom needs a new king.
王国需要一位新的国王
You and Fiona are next in line for the throne.
你和菲奥娜将即位王座
Next in line. You see, Dad, that's why people love you.
即位？你看，爸爸 这就是为什么人民爱戴你的原因
Even on your deathbed, you're still making jokes.
即使临终之时，你还在开玩笑
Oome on, Dad. An ogre as king?
得了吧，爸爸，怪物做国王？
That's not such a good idea.
这不是个好主意
There must be somebody else. Anybody!
必须有另外的人来继任，任何人！
Aside from you, there is only one remaining heir.
除了你，只有一个继承人
Really? Who is he, Dad?
真的？是谁？爸爸
His name is...
他叫…
...is...
叫…
What's his name?
他叫什么？
...is...
叫…
Daddy!
爸爸！
His name is Arthur.
他叫亚瑟
Arthur?
亚瑟？
I know you'll do...what's right.
我知道你会…处理好这件事的
Harold?
哈罗德？
Dad? Dad!
爸爸？爸爸！
Dad?
爸爸？
Do your thing, man.
脱帽，朋友
∮ When you were young and your heart ∮
∮ 当你年轻的时候，你的心 ∮
∮ Was an open book ∮
∮ 是一本打开的书 ∮
∮ You used to say live and let live ∮
∮ 你以前常说活着，让活着 ∮
∮ You know you did, you know you did You know you did ∮
∮ 你知道你做了，你知道你做了 ∮
∮ But if this ever changing world In which we live in ∮
∮ 但是如果我们生活的这个不断变化的世界 ∮
∮ Makes you give in and cry ∮
∮ 让你屈服并哭泣 ∮
∮ Say live and let die ∮
∮ 说生与死 ∮
∮ Live and let die ∮
∮ 生与死 ∮
∮ Hey, lady You, lady ∮
∮ 嘿，小姐，小姐 ∮
∮ Cursing at your life ∮
∮ 诅咒你的生命 ∮
∮ You're a discontented mother ∮
∮ 你是个不满的母亲 ∮
∮ And a regimented wife ∮
∮ 和一个受约束的妻子 ∮
What does a prince have to do to get a drink here?
王子想在这儿喝酒该怎么做呢？
Ah, Mabel!
啊，梅波
Why they call you an ugly stepsister, I'll never know.
为什么他们叫你丑陋的继姐 我一直不明白
Where's Doris? Taking the night off?
多丽丝呢？今晚休息？
She's not welcome here, and neither are you.
这里不欢迎她，你也一样
What do you want, Oharming?
你想要干吗，查明？
Not much. Just a chance at redemption.
没什么，想找个机会赎罪
And a Fuzzy Navel.
一杯鸡尾酒
And Fuzzy Navels for all my friends!
给在场所有我的朋友们一杯鸡尾酒
We're not your friends.
我们不是你的朋友
You don't belong here.
你不属于这里
You're absolutely right, but, I mean, do any of us?
你说得对，但我意思是 有谁属于这里呢？
Do a number on his face.
在他脸上做个记号
Wait, wait, wait! We are more alike than you think.
等等，等等 我们其实都一样
Wicked Witch! The Seven Dwarfs saved Snow White, and what happened?
丑巫婆！七个小矮人救了白雪公主 然后发生了什么？
Oh, what's it to you?
这和你有什么关系？
They left you the unfairest of them all.
他们给了你最不公平的待遇
Now here you are, hustling pool to get your next meal.
现在你在这里 靠台球来换取你的下一顿饭
How does that feel?
那感觉怎样？
Pretty unfair.
很不公平
And you!
还有你！
Your star puppet abandons the show to go and find his father.
你的明星木偶放弃了表演 去寻找他的父亲
I hate that little wooden puppet.
我讨厌那个小木头玩偶
And Hook.
还有你铁钩
Need I say more?
还需要我说吗？
- And you, Frumpypigskin! - Rumpelstiltskin.
- 你，弗朗皮克斯金 - 是兰佩尔斯汀斯金
Where's that firstborn you were promised?
他们保证你的长子又在哪里呢？
Mabel. Remember how you couldn't get your little fat foot...
梅波，记住你是怎么不能把你的肥脚丫…
...into that tiny glass slipper?
穿进那个小的水晶鞋的吗？
Oinderella is in Far Far Away right now...
灰姑娘此刻正在遥远国…
...eating bonbons, cavorting with every last fairy tale creature...
正吃着糖果和那些
...that has ever done you wrong!
和你作对的人快乐着呢
Once upon a time, someone decided that we were the losers.
从前，一些人把我们称为失败者
But there are two sides to every story...
但每个故事都有两面
...and our side has not been told!
我们的那一面还没有讲给人听
So who will join me? Who wants to come out on top for once?
所以谁要加入我？谁想要翻身一次？
Who wants their...
谁想要…
"Happily ever after"?
从此以后一直幸福？
This way, gents.
这边，绅士们
It's out of my hands, senorita. The winds of fate have blown on my destiny.
人在江湖，身不由己啊
But I will never forget you. You are the love of my life.
但我永远不会忘记你 你是我一生的爱
As are you.
你也是
And, uh, you.
还有你
I don't know you, but I'd like to.
我不认识你，但我也愿意
I got to go!
我要走了
I don't wanna leave you either.
我也不想离开你们
But you know how Shrek is. The dude's lost without me.
但你知道史莱克是怎样的 这兄弟没有我就不行
But don't worry. I'll send you airmail kisses every day!
不要担心，我会每天给你快递香吻的
Be strong, babies.
要坚强，孩子们
Ooco, Peanut, listen to your mama.
椰子，花生，听妈妈的话
Bananas, no roasting marshmallows on your sister's head.
香蕉，不要再在你妹妹头上烤蜜饯了哦
That's my special boy!
那才是我的乖孩子
Oome here, all of you! Give your daddy a big hug!
都过来，给你们老爸一个大大的拥抱
Shrek?
史莱克？
Maybe you should just stay and be King.
也许你该留下继任国王
Oome on. There's no way I could run a kingdom.
得了吧，我怎么可能来管理国家
That's why your cousin Arthur is a perfect choice.
你的堂弟亚瑟才是个完美的选择
It's not that. You see...
不是的，你知道…
And if he gives me trouble, I always have persuasion and reason.
如果他给我麻烦 我可以说服他给他讲道理
Here's persuasion... and here's reason.
这法宝是说服力，这法宝是讲道理
Fiona...
菲奥娜…
...soon it's just going to be you, me...
很快就只有你和我…
...and our swamp.
还有我们的沼泽
It's not going to be just you and me.
不只是你和我
All aboard!
上船啦！
It will be. I promise.
会的，我保证
I love you.
我爱你
（我们爱你，爸爸）
That's lovely.
太美了
Bye-bye, babies!
再见，孩子们！
Shrek!
史莱克！
- Wait! - What is it?
- 等等 - 什么？
I'm... I'm...
我…
I love you, too, honey!
我也爱你，亲爱的！
No! I said I'm...
不！我说，我…
You're what?
你什么？
I said I'm pregnant!
我说我怀孕了！
What was that?
那是什么？
You're going to be a father!
你要做父亲了！
That's great!
太好了！
Really? I'm glad you think so!
真的？我很高兴你这么想
I love you!
我爱你！
Yeah!
嗯！
Me, too! You!
我也爱你！
I'm going to be an uncle! I'm going to be an uncle!
我要做叔叔了！ 我要做叔叔了！
And you, my friend, are royally...
你，我的朋友，将成为皇室…
Home.
家
Shrek!
史莱克！
Fiona!
菲奥娜！
Fiona?
菲奥娜？
Oh, no.
哦，不
Better out than in, I always say.
我一直说，能吃下去就别吐出来
No, no, no!
不，不，不！
It's okay. It's gonna be all right.
没事的，会没事的
Stop! Hey, wait!
住手，嘿，等等！
Donkey. Donkey!
驴子！驴子！
Wake up!
醒醒！
Dada!
爸爸！
Shrek! Are you okay?
史莱克？你好吧？
I can't believe I'm going to be a father. How did this happen?
我不敢相信我要做父亲了 这怎么发生的？
Allow me to explain. When a man has feelings for a woman...
请允许我解释，当一个男人 对一个女人有感觉时…
...a powerful urge sweeps over him.
一股强大的冲动占据着他
I know how it happened.
我知道这是怎么发生的
I just can't believe it.
我只是不敢相信
How does it happen?
这是怎么发生的？
∮ And the cat's in the cradle and the silver spoon ∮
∮ 还有猫在摇篮里和银勺 ∮
∮ Little Boy Blue and the Man in the Moon ∮
∮ 蓝色小男孩和月亮上的人 ∮
∮ When you coming home, son? I don't know when ∮
∮ 你什么时候回家，儿子？我不知道什么时候 ∮
∮ But we'll get together then, Dad ∮
∮ 但我们到时候会聚在一起的，爸爸 ∮
Donkey! Oan you just cut to the part
驴子！你能不能只唱…
where you're supposed to make me feel better?
让我感觉舒服的部分？
You know I love Fiona, boss. Right?
你知道我很爱菲奥娜，对吧，老大？
What I am talking about is you, me, my cousin's boat...
我要说的是你，我还有我堂弟的船…
...an ice cold pitcher of mojitos and two weeks of nothing but fishing.
再来一壶冰酒，加上两个礼拜的钓鱼
Don't listen to him!
不要听他的！
Having a baby isn't going to ruin your life.
有孩子不会毁掉你的生活
It's not my life I'm worried about ruining, it's the kid's.
我担心的不是毁掉我的生活 而是孩子的生活
When have you ever heard the phrase "as sweet as an ogre"...
你听到过别人说“像怪物一样美”…
...or "as nurturing as an ogre"...
或是”像怪物一样有教养“
...or "You'll love my dad. He's a real ogre."
或是”你会喜欢我爸爸的 他是个真正的怪物“这样的话吗？
Okay. I get it.
好，我懂了
It's not going to be easy. But you got us to help you.
虽然这不会那么容易 但你有我们的帮助
That's true.
那倒是
I'm doomed.
命中注定的
You'll be fine.
你会好的
You're finished.
你完了
Uh, with yourjourney.
哦，完…成了你的旅程
"Wor-ces-ters-shiree"? Now that sounds fancy!
”沃…册特…斯里？“ 听上去很新奇！
It's Worcestershire.
是沃塞斯特雷
Like the sauce?
和那个沙司牌子一样？
It's spicy!
好香！
They must be expecting us.
他们肯定在期待我们
What in the shista-shire kind of place is this?
这个沃什么的到底是个什么地方？
Well, my stomach aches and my palms just got sweaty. Must be a high school.
我的胃好疼还有我的手掌在出汗 一定是个中学
High school?
中学？
Ready? Okay!
好了吗？开始
Wherefore art thou headed, to the top?
“你想到达艺术的顶端吗?”
Yeah, we think so, we think so! And dost thou thinkest thine can be stopped?
“是啊，我们能，我们能！ 有什么能阻止你呢？”
Nay, we thinkst not, we thinkst not!
“不，没有，没有”
All right, Mr. Percival, ease up on the reins.
好，佩西，脱缰一样冲吧
For lo, bro, don't burn all my frankincense and myrrh.
伙计，别烧了我的乳香和没药
I'm feeling nauseous from memories of wedgies and swirlies!
那平底鞋和混乱场面让我感到恶心
How did you receive wedgies when you are clearly not the wearer of underpants?
你不穿内裤哪来的平底鞋呢？
Let's just say some things are better left unsaid.
有些事是不言而喻的
So I was all like, "I'd rather get the black plague than go out with you."
所以我要说“我宁愿得黑死病 也不愿和你出去约会”
- Oh, totally. - Pardon me.
- 哦，绝对的 - 你说什么
- Totally ew-eth. - Yeah, totally.
- 绝对恶心 - 是啊
I just altered my character level to +3 superb-ability.
我刚把我的角色等级升到了+3超能力
Hi. We're looking for someone named...
嗨，我们在找一个叫…
Who rolled a +9 dork spell and summoned the beast and his quadruped?
谁弄了+9的傀儡符咒 又召唤了怪物和四足怪？
I know you're busy not fitting in, but can you tell me where I can find Arthur?
我知道你们很忙没时间 但你们能告诉我哪里能找到亚瑟吗？
He's over there.
他在那里
There is no sweeter taste on thy tongue than victory!
没有比胜利更美味的了
Strong, handsome, face of a leader.
强壮，英俊，长着一张领导者的脸
Does Arthur look like a king or what?
亚瑟长得不就像一位国王吗？
Sorry.
不好意思
Did you say you were looking for Arthur?
你刚才说你在找亚瑟？
That information is on a need-to-know basis.
显而易见的
It's top secret!
这是顶级机密！
Now, gentlemen, let's away. To the showers!
先生们，我们走 去洗澡！
Greetings, Your Majesty.
你好，陛下
This is your lucky day.
今天是你的幸运日
What are you supposed to be?
你是什么东西？
Some kind of giant mutant leprechaun or something?
某种变异的巨大妖精还是什么？
Giant mutant... You made a funny.
变异？你真搞笑
Unhand me, monster!
放我下来，怪物！
Stop squirming, Arthur.
不要动，亚瑟
I'm not Arthur.
我不是亚瑟
I am Lancelot.
我是兰斯洛特
That dork over there is Arthur.
那边的那个傻瓜才是亚瑟
This is, like, totally embarrassing...
这…真的是…很尴尬
...but Tiffany thinkest thou vex her so soothly.
但蒂凡尼对你很有兴趣
She thought perchance thou would ask her to the Homecoming Dance.
她想你会不会愿意邀请她去“回归舞会”
Excuse me?
什么？
Like, whatever. She's into college guys and mythical creatures.
这样的，她对大学男生 还有神话怪物很感兴趣
Oh, Arthur...
哦，亚瑟…
...come out, come out, wherever you are!
出来，出来，不管你在哪里
You better run, you little punk no-goodniks!
你们最好走远点，混蛋！
The days of Donkey Dumpy Drawers are over!
贫嘴驴短内裤的日子结束了
Hold it.
等等
We're here for the mascot contest.
我们是来参加吉祥物比赛的
We're here for the mascot contest, too.
我们也是来参加吉祥物比赛的
This is a costume?
这是服装吗？
Worked on it all night long.
我弄了整整一晚上呢
Looks pretty real to me.
看上去象真的一样
If he were real, could I do this?
如果他是真的，我能这样做吗？
Or this?
或是这样？
If it were real, that would have been agonizingly painful.
如果是真的，早就疼得要命了
- Now watch this! - That's quite enough, boys.
- 看好这个！ - 够了，孩子们
Thank you to Professor Primbottom and his lecture...on "just say nay".
谢谢普林波顿教授和他的“只要说不”演讲
And now, without further ado, let's give a warm Worcestershire hoozah...
现在不再啰唆，让我们热烈…
...to the winner of our mascot contest, the...
欢迎吉祥物大赛的冠军…
...ogre?
怪物？
That's right. I'm the new mascot.
对，我是新的吉祥物
So let's really try and beat the other guys at...
我们还是热烈的为那些…
...whatever it is they're doing!
不知道在干吗的人鼓掌吧！
This is all a bit unorthodox...
这太不正统了
Where can I find Arthur Pendragon?
哪里我能找到亚瑟·潘德拉根？
Hey, wait...
嘿，等等…
Olassic.
经典
You should be ashamed of yourself!
你该为自己感到羞愧！
I didn't do it. They did.
不是我干的，是他们干的
Please don't eat me.
请不要吃掉我
Eat him! Eat him! Eat him!
吃掉他！吃掉他！吃掉他！
I'm not here to eat him!
我不是来吃他的！
Time to pack up your toothbrush and jammies.
你该打包整理你的行李了
You're the new King of Far Far Away.
你将是遥远国新的国王
What?
什么？
Artie a king? More like the Mayor of Loserville!
亚蒂王？ 他更像是笨蛋村的村长！
Is this for real?
这是真的吗？
Absolutely. Olean out your locker, kid. You have a kingdom to run.
当然，清理好你的衣柜，孩子 你的王国等着你管理
So, wait... l'm really the only heir?
等等…我真的是唯一的继承人？
The one and only.
唯一的一个
Give me a second.
等我一下
My good people...
我的人民…
...there's a lesson here for all of us.
这是非常好的一课
Next time you're about to dunk a kid's head in a chamber pot, stop and think,
下一次你们准备把一个小孩的头 泡在尿壶里的时候，请停下想想
"Hey, maybe this guy has feelings.
“嘿，也许这个家伙也是有感情的”
Maybe I should cut him some slack.
“也许我该放他一马”
'Oause maybe... just maybe...
“也许因为…也许…”
...this guy's gonna turn out to be, I don't know, a king?
“这家伙会成为，有可能，成为国王？”
Maybe his first royal decree will be to banish everyone who ever picked on him."
也许他颁布的第一个皇家法令就是 放逐那些曾经戏弄过他的人
I'm looking at you, jousting team!
我在看着你，骑马队！
And Guin? Oh, Guin.
还有奎因？哦，奎因
I've always loved you.
我一直爱着你
Good friends, it breaks my heart, but...
好朋友们，我很伤心，但…
...enjoy your stay here in prison while I rule the free world!
你们继续享受在这牢狱里的日子吧 而我将去统治一个自由的世界
Okay, let's not overdo it.
好了，我们不要搞的太过了
I'm building my city, people... on rock 'n' roll!
我将建立我的城市，摇滚的人民
You just overdid it.
你做得太过了
Look at you!
看看你啊！
You look darling.
你看上去真可爱
Just precious. Look at her.
太尊贵了，看她
Any cravings since you got pregnant?
从你怀孕后有什么特别渴望的吗？
No. Not at all.
没，一点也没
Do you smell ham?
你们闻到火腿的味道了吗？
It's present time!
现在是礼物时间！
Fiona, please open mine first. It's the one in front.
菲奥娜，请先打开我的礼物 前面的那个
"Oongratulations on your new mess mak..." Oh, mess maker!
“恭喜你要有调皮鬼了” 哦，调皮鬼！
"Hopefully this helps. Love, Oinderella."
“希望这对你有用，爱你的，灰姑娘”
- Look at that! - What is it?
- 看看那个！ - 那是什么？
It's for the poopies.
用来打扫大便的
Wait... babies poop?
等等…婴儿的大便？
Everyone poops, Beauty.
每个人都大便的，睡美人
Fiona!
菲奥娜！
We all chipped in for a little present, too.
我们也都准备了一个小礼物
Ta-da!
哒…哒！
You know the baby will love it, because I do!
你知道孩子会喜欢的 因为我也喜欢！
Guys, that's so sweet. Thank you.
伙计们，你们真是太好了，谢谢
Who's this one from?
这是谁给的？
I got you the biggest one, because I love you most.
我给你最大的礼物 因为爱你也最深
"Have one on me. Love, Snow White."
“我也想有个，爱你的，白雪公主”
What is it?
这是什么？
He's a live-in babysitter.
专职婴儿保姆
Where's the baby?
宝宝在哪里？
You're too kind, Snow, but I can't accept this.
你太好了，白雪公主 但我不能收下
It's nothing. I have six more at home.
没什么的，我家里还有6个呢
- What does he do? - Oleaning.
- 他能做什么？ - 打扫
- Feeding. - Burping.
- 喂饭 - 打嗝
So, what are Shrek and I supposed to do?
那我和史莱克该干吗？
Work on your marriage.
享受你们的婚姻
Thanks, Rapunzel. What's that supposed to mean?
谢谢，莴苣姑娘 那是什么意思？
Oome on now, Fiona. You know what happens.
得了，菲奥娜 你知道怎么回事
You're tired all the time.
你一直很劳累
You start letting yourself go.
失去了真正的自己
Stretch marks.
妊娠纹
Say goodbye to romance.
再也没有浪漫生活
I'm sorry, but how many of you have kids?
不好意思，但你们中有几个有孩子呢？
She's right!
她说的对
A baby will only strengthen the love Shrek and Fiona have.
孩子只会加深史莱克和菲奥娜之间的爱
How did Shrek react when you told him?
当你告诉史莱克时，他是什么反应？
When he first found out, Shrek said...
当他第一次知道时，他说…
Onward, my new friends! To our happily ever afters!
冲啊，我的新朋友们！ 为了我们永远的幸福生活！
Now... bombs away!
现在，投弹！
Well, well, well. If it isn't Peter Pan.
好，好，好，如果这不是皮特·潘
- His name's not Peter. - Shut it, Wendy.
- 他不叫皮特 - 闭嘴，温迪
Enough pillaging! To the castle!
掠夺够了！向城堡冲啊！
You go! Take care of the baby!
你们快走！照顾好孩子！
Everybody stay calm! We're going to die!
大家冷静！我们要死了！
Everyone in! Now!
大家快进去！快！
Oome on! Put some back into it!
快，撞开！
We don't have time. Now go!
我们没时间了，快走！
Quickly, ladies!
快点，女士们！
We'll hold them off as long as we can!
我们尽量拖延住他们！
Where are Shrek and Fiona?
史莱克和菲奥娜在哪里？
The name doesn't ring a bell.
从没听说过这名字
No bell.
没听过
I suggest you freaks cooperate...
我建议你们这群蠢蛋…
...with the new King of Far Far Away!
好好的跟遥远国的新国王合作！
The only thing you're ever gonna be king of is King of the Stupids!
你唯一可以成为的是傻瓜国的国王！
- Hook! - Right!
- 铁钩！ - 在！
Avast, ye cookie.
来吧，你这小饼干
Start talking.
说话呀
- Gingy! - Papa!
- 金吉！ - 爸爸！
Settle down now.
大家坐下！
On the good ship Lollipop
坐上漂亮船去买棒棒糖
It's a sweet trip to the candy shop
去糖果店的旅程真是太美好了
You!
你！
You can't lie.
你不会说谎的
So tell me, puppet... where is Shrek?
告诉我，木偶…史莱克在哪里？
Well... I don't know where he's not.
那…我不知道他不在哪里
You don't know where Shrek is?
你不知道史莱克在哪里？
It wouldn't be inaccurate to assume...
不能不正确的假定…
...that I couldn't exactly not say that is or isn't almost partially incorrect.
我不能确切的不说出 或部分不几乎是不正确
So you do know where he is!
那你肯定是知道他在哪里！
On the contrary, I'm possibly more or less
恰恰相反，我可能或多或少
not definitely rejecting the idea that in no way, with any amount of uncertainty...
不确定的不完全否定这个意思
Stop it!
住嘴！
...I do not know where he shouldn't be.
我不知道他不应该在哪里
If that indeed wasn't where he isn't.
如果确实那不是他不在的地方
Even if he wasn't not where I knew he was, it could mean...
即使他不是不在我所知道的他在的地方 这意味着…
On the good ship Lollipop
坐上漂亮的船去买棒棒糖
Enough! Shrek went off to bring back the next heir!
够了！史莱克出去要把下一任的国王带回来
He's bringing back the next heir?
他要带回下一任的国王？
No!
不！
Hook! Get rid of this new "King".
铁钩！去除掉这个新“国王”
But bring Shrek to me.
但把史莱克带来给我
I have something special in mind for him.
我给他准备了特别的主意
He'll never fall for your tricks!
他绝不会被你的诡计陷害的
Oh, boy.
哦，孩子
I can't believe it. Me, a king?
我真不敢相信，我，一个国王？
I knew I came from royalty, but...
我知道我出身皇室，但…
...I figured everyone forgot about me.
我原以为大家都忘记了我
Oh, no. In fact the King asked for you personally.
哦，不，实际上是国王亲自点名要你继任的
Really? Wow.
真的？哇
But I know it's not all fun and games.
但我知道这不是玩游戏
It really is all fun and games, actually.
事实上这确实是玩游戏
Sure, you have to knight a few heroes, launch a ship or two.
当然，你要册封一些新英雄 启航一两艘舰船
By the way, make sure you hit the boat just right with the bottle.
顺便说一下，你务必确保 能用瓶子击中轮船
Any idiot can hit a boat with a bottle.
任何傻瓜都能用一个瓶子击中一艘轮船
Well, I've heard it's harder than it looks.
我听说这其实要比看上去来的困难
This is going to be huge.
这真是太棒了
Parties, princesses, castles. Princesses.
聚会，公主，城堡，公主
You'll be living in the lap of luxury.
你会生活的很奢侈
The finest chefs will wait for your order.
最好的厨师会等候你的命令
And fortunately, you'll have the royal food tasters.
幸运的是，你还会有皇家食物品尝师
What do they do?
他们是做什么的？
Taste the food before the King eats, to make sure it's not poisoned.
在国王吃东西前先品尝 确保食物没有被放毒
- Poisoned? - Or too salty.
- 放毒？ - 或者太咸了
Don't worry. Your bodyguards will keep you safe.
不要担心，你的侍卫会保护你的安全
All of them willing at a moment's notice
他们愿意随时随地的牺牲自己…
to lay down their lives out of devotion to you.
为了保护你的生命
Really?
真的？
The whole kingdom will look to you for wisdom and guidance.
整个国家都指望着你的智慧和指引
Make sure they don't die of famine!
确保他们不会死于饥饿
- Or plague. - Plague is bad.
- 或是瘟疫 - 瘟疫太糟了
The coughing, the groaning, the festering sores.
咳嗽，呻吟，化脓溃疡
Festering sores! You are one funny kitty cat.
化脓溃疡！ 你真是个有趣的可爱小猫
What did I say?
我刚才说什么了？
We don't want Artie getting the wrong idea.
我们不想让亚蒂有错误的想法
Artie?
亚蒂？
There goes my hip!
够郁闷的！
Artie! What are you doing?
亚蒂！你在干吗？
What does it look like?!
你看我在干吗？！
This really isn't up to you.
这真的不是你该做的
I don't know anything about being king!
我对于当国王一无所知
You'll learn on the job!
你会慢慢学会的！
Sorry, but I'm going back.
不好意思，但我准备回去
Back to what? Being a loser?
回去哪里？去当一个失败者？
Now look what you did!
看看你做的好事！
Look what I did? Who's holding the wheel, chief?
看看我做的好事？ 是谁在掌舵啊，大幅？
Shrek!
史莱克！
Land ho!
上岸！
How humiliating.
真是丢脸
Oh, nice going, Your Highness.
哦，做得好，殿下
Now it's "Your Highness"? What happened to "loser"?
现在成了“殿下”？ 刚才谁在叫“失败者”？
If you think this is getting you out of anything, it isn't.
如果你认为这就能使你离开 那是不可能的
We're heading back to Far Far Away one way or another...
我们无论如何会回到遥远国
...and you're going to be a father!
而你将会成为父亲！
What?
什么？
You just said "father".
你刚才说“父亲”
King! You're going to be king!
国王！你将会成为国王！
"You're going to be king!" Yeah, right.
“你会成为国王”是啊，对的
Where are you going?
你去哪里？
Far Far Away... from you!
远远…的离开你
Get back here, young man!
回来，年轻人！
Boss? I don't think he's coming back.
老大？我认为他不回来了
Maybe it's for the best. He's not exactly king material.
也许这是对的 他真的不是当国王的料
When did you plan to tell him you were supposed to be king?
那你计划什么时候告诉他 你才应该当国王？
Oome on. Why would I do that?
得了，我为什么要那么做？
Besides, he'll be ten times better at it than me.
而且，他做国王比我强十倍
Then change your tactics if you want to get anywhere with him.
如果你想要他跟你走 你需要改变你的战略
You're right, Donkey.
你说得对，驴子
What about this?
这个怎样？
- Shrek! - Oome on. It's just a joke.
- 史莱克！ - 得了，只是个玩笑
Still...
算是吧…
Listen, Artie.
听着，亚蒂
If you think this whole mad scene ain't dope, I feel you, dude.
如果你觉得这整件事情很糟糕 我理解你，兄弟
I'm not trying to get up in your grill or raise your roof.
我不想难为你，让你心烦意乱
But what I am screamin' is, yo...
但我想要说的是，你…
...check out this kazing thazing, bazaby!
想想这整个事情，孩子！
If it doesn't groove, or what I'm saying
如果这不合理，或是我所说的…
ain't straight trippin', say, "Oh, no, you didn't!
不够真诚，你可以直接说 “哦，不，你别”
You're getting on my last nerve."
“你快让我疯了”
And then I'll know it's... I'll know it's wack!
那么我会知道这是… 知道这是不值得的
Help!
救命啊！
I've been kidnapped by a monster who's trying to relate to me!
我被一个怪物绑架了 他想跟我拉关系
- Artie, wait. - Oome on! Help! Hello?
- 亚蒂，等等 - 快点！救命！有人吗？
Greetings, cosmic children of the universe.
大家好，宇宙的孩子们
Welcome to my serenity circle.
欢迎来到我的宁静之处
Please leave any bad vibes outside the healing vortex.
请不要带坏的电颤琴到康复小屋里来
Now prepare to...
现在准备好…
I knew I should have got that warranty!
我就知道我该拿保修单的！
Mr. Merlin?
梅林先生？
You know this guy?
你认识这个人？
Yeah. He was the school magic teacher, until he had his nervous breakdown.
是啊，他没神经失常前 是学校里的魔法老师
Technically, I was merely a victim of a level 3 fatigue.
专业点讲，我只是3等疲劳
At the request of my therapist,
在我的理疗师
and the school authorities, I retired to the tranquility of nature
和学校方面要求下 我退休来享受宁静世界
to discover my divine purpose.
为了发现我神圣的目标
Oan I interest anyone in a snack or beverage?
谁有兴趣来点小吃或是饮料吗？
Uh, no.
哦，不了
Sure you don't want to try my Rock Au Gratin?
你确定不想尝尝我的烤脆皮面包？
It's organic.
是有机的哦
Thanks. I ate a boulder on the way in.
谢谢了，我来的途中吃了一大块圆石
We need directions to Far Far Away.
我们需要去遥远国的线路
"We"? Who said I was going with you?
“我们”？谁说我要和你一起去？
I did. People are counting on you, so don't try to weasel out of it.
我说的，人民指望着你 所以不要再躲避了
If the job's so great, you do it.
如果那份差事真的那么好，你去做好了
Understand this, kid. No more Mr. Nice Guy from here on out.
你要明白，孩子 现在再也没有什么好人了
That was your Mr. Nice Guy?
他就是你的所谓好人？
Yeah, and I'm going to miss him.
是的，我会想念他的
Why don't you go terrorize a village and leave me alone!
为什么你不自己去恐吓村庄 别管我！
Was that a crack about ogres? You get your royal highness to Far Far Away...
那就是怪物的爆发吗？ 在我没发飙前…
...before I kick it there! Now, which way am I kicking?
你最好给我回遥远国去当国王 我该怎么发飙？
I could tell you, but since you're
我可以告诉你，但由于你…
in the midst of a self-destructive rage spiral,
正处于自我毁灭的怒火漩涡之中
it would be karmically irresponsible.
告诉你是不负责任
Self-destructive? Are you going to help us or not?
自我毁灭？ 你帮不帮我们？
Most definitely, but only after you
肯定帮，但只有在你…
take the journey to your soul!
进行了心灵之旅后！
I don't think so.
我不这么认为
It's either that or primal scream therapy.
要么就是这个，要么就进行心理治疗
All right. Journey to the soul.
好的，心灵之旅
Now, all of you,
现在，你们所有人…
look into the Fire of Truth
都给我注视着这真理之火
and tell me what you see.
然后告诉我你们看到了什么
Ooh, charades!
哦，手势猜谜游戏！
Okay, I see a Dutch fudge torte with cinnamon swirls!
好，我看到了一个有肉桂卷的荷兰软糖馅饼
Okay, monster... go for it.
好，怪物，该你了
I see a rainbow pony.
我看到了一匹彩虹小马
Excellent work! Now the boy.
做得好！该你了，孩子
This is lame.
这太废了
You're lame! Now just go for it.
你才废！快试一下
Okay.
好的
There's a baby bird and a father bird sitting in a nest.
有一个小鸟还有个鸟爸爸，坐在鸟巢里
Yes! Stay with it!
好！继续！
The dad just flew away. Why did he leave the little bird all alone?
爸爸飞走了，他为什么单独留下了小鸟？
It's trying to fly, but it doesn't know how to.
小鸟试着飞行，但它不会飞
It's going to fall!
它要掉下来了
Proper head case you are. Really messed up.
你还真是个疯子 一塌糊涂
Okay, I get it. The bird's me. My dad left. So what?
好，我懂了，小鸟是我 我爸爸离开了，那又怎样
Look, Artie, um...
听着，亚蒂
Just thought I'd help set the mood...
只是想给你们制造…
...for your big heart-to-heart chat.
美好的心对心谈话的气氛
I know what it's like to not feel ready for something.
我知道对于一件事还没准备好 是一种什么感觉
Even ogres get scared.
即使怪物也会觉得担心
You know... once in a while.
你知道…偶尔
I know you want me to be king, but I can't.
我知道你要我成为国王，但我不能
I'm not cut out for it, and I never will be.
我不适合当国王，而且永远也不可能
Even my own dad knew I wasn't worth the trouble.
即使我亲身父亲也觉得我一无是处
He dumped me at that school first chance he got...
他第一时间把我扔到了那个学校
...and I never heard from him again.
我就再也没有听到过他的消息
My dad wasn't really the fatherly type, either.
我爸爸也不配做父亲
I doubt he was worse than mine.
我怀疑他比我的爸爸还差
Oh, yeah?
哦，是吗？
My father was an ogre. He tried to eat me.
我爸爸是个怪物，他想吃掉我
I guess I should have realized it.
我猜我本该意识到的
He bathed me in barbecue sauce and put me to bed with an apple in my mouth.
他拿烧烤调味酱给我洗澡 拿苹果塞着我的嘴放我在床上
I guess that's pretty bad.
我想那真是太糟了
It may be hard to believe,
这也许很难相信…
what, with my obvious charm and good looks,
我那显而易见迷人漂亮的外貌…
but people used to think I was a monster.
但在过去一直认为我是个怪物
And for a long time, I believed them.
曾经一度，我也相信了他们
But after a while,
但后来
you learn to ignore the names people call you
你学会了忽视别人怎么称呼你
and just trust who you are.
只要相信自己
You know... you're okay, Shrek.
你知道的，你人很好，史莱克
You just need to do a little less yelling and use a little more soap.
你只要稍微减少大吼的次数 多用用肥皂就可以了
Thanks, Artie.
谢谢，亚蒂
The soap's because you stink... really bad.
肥皂是因为你发臭时…真的是太糟了
Yeah... I got that.
是啊，我明白了
This place is filthy!
这地方真是太脏了！
I feel like a hobo.
我感觉自己像是个流浪汉
I'm sorry, but this isn't working for me.
不好意思，但这地方让我很难受
Everything's always about you. It's not like your attitude is helping.
你只关心你自己 你的态度不能对我们有任何帮助
Maybe itjust bothers you I was voted fairest in the land.
也许是我被选为国家最美的 这一事实打击了你
You mean in that rigged election?
你是说那次作弊的选美？
Give me a break. "Rapunzel, Rapunzel...
得了吧，“莴苣姑娘 莴苣姑娘…
...let down thy golden extensions!"
放下你的金色假发！”
Ladies, let go of your petty complaints and let's work together!
女士们，不要再相互抱怨了 我们要齐心协力
So I guess the plan is we just wander aimlessly
我猜这计划就是我们毫无目的的…
in this stinkhole until we rot.
在这臭气熏天的洞里闲逛直到我们腐烂
No, we get inside and find out what Oharming's up to.
不，我们要进去，去探明查明的目的
I know he's a jerk and everything,
我知道他是个混蛋
but that Oharming makes me hotter than July.
但查明真是性感
That's it!
就是那个！
Oome on! This way!
快点！这边！
Rapunzel, wait!
莴苣，等等
Oharming, let go of her.
查明，放开她
But why would I want to do that?
我为什么要那么做？
What?
什么？
Say hello, ladies, to the new Queen of Far Far Away.
女士们，向你们遥远国的新女皇问好
Rapunzel, how could you?
莴苣，你怎么能这样？
Jealous much?
妒忌吧？
Soon you'll be back where you started,
很快你就会回到当初…
scrubbing floors or locked away in towers.
你擦地板，被锁在塔楼里的时代了
That is, if I let you last the week.
我会让你在这里多呆一个礼拜
Pookie, you promised not to hurt them.
波齐，你答应过不伤害他们的
Not here, kitten whiskers. Daddy will discuss it later.
等会儿，宝贝，我们晚点再说
Now forgive us. We have a show to put on.
见谅，我们要去赶演出
Shrek will be back soon, and you'll be sorry.
史莱克很快就回来了 你会后悔的
Sorry?!
后悔？！
Don't you realize once Shrek sets foot in Far Far Away...
你没意识到只要 史莱克一涉足遥远国…
...he's doomed?
他就完蛋了？
Look out! They got a piano!
当心！他们有钢琴！
Kill them all... except the fat one.
把他们全杀了…除了那个胖的
King Oharming has something special in mind for you, ogre.
查明国王有特殊的主意留给你，怪物
King Oharming?
查明国王？
Attack!
攻击！
Artie, duck!
亚蒂，蹲下！
Ready the plank!
准备好木板！
- Shrek! - Help!
- 史莱克！ - 救命！
Oowards!
冲啊！
What has Oharming done with Fiona?
查明把菲奥娜怎么了？
She's going to get what's coming to her.
她已经束手就擒了
And there ain't nothing you can do to stop him!
你已经无能为力去救她了
- We've got to save her. - But she's so far far away!
- 我们必须去救她 - 但我们离她太远了！
Get yourself back to Worcestershire, kid.
你自己回沃塞斯特雷吧，孩子
No, Shrek. Hold on. I've got an idea.
不，史莱克，等等 我有个主意
I am a buzzing bee.
我是个嗡嗡小蜜蜂
Mr. Merlin? They need a spell to get them...
梅林先生？他们需要一个符咒…
...I mean us, back to Far Far Away.
我是说我们需要回到遥远国
Forget it. I don't have that kind of magic in me anymore.
没门，我没有那种魔法能力了
How about a hug? That's the best kind of magic.
拥抱一下怎样？ 那是最好的魔法
Please. I know you can do it.
梅林先生，求你了 我知道你可以的
I said forget it!
我说了没门！
But...
但…
What's with you?
你怎么了？
It's just so hard, you know?
这太难受了，你知道吗？
They need to get back, 'cause their kingdom's in trouble.
他们需要回去 因为他们的国家正面临困境
'Oause there's a really bad man.
因为那里有个坏人
It's just so hard!
这太伤心了！
Take it easy.
好了，别激动
No! I don't think you understand!
不！我想你肯定不理解！
There's a mean person doing mean things to good people.
有个卑鄙的家伙正对 一群好人做着卑鄙的事
Have a heart, old man.
发发慈悲吧，老人
They really need your help to get back. Why won't you help them?!
他们真的需要你帮助他们回去 为什么你不愿帮他们呢？
Okay.
好的
I'll go get my things.
我去拿我的东西
Piece of cake.
小菜一碟
Well, well. You want eggs with that ham?
那你想要点火腿鸡蛋吗？
I am a little rusty, so there could be some side effects.
我有点生疏了，因此这可能造成些副作用
- Side effects? - Don't worry.
- 副作用？ - 不用担心
Whatever it is, no matter how excruciatingly painful,
不管什么副作用，无论这有多么痛苦
it will wear off eventually. I think.
我想最终这副作用会慢慢消失的
- Oops. - You sure about this?
- 哦，不 - 你确信？
If Artie trusts him, that's good enough for me.
如果亚蒂相信他，那我也肯定相信
Even if his robe doesn't cover...
即使他的长袍没有盖住…
Alacritious expeditious...
[咒语] 玛咪玛咪！轰！
...a-zoomy-zoom-zoom!
[咒语] 啊…儒咪！
Let's help our friends get back...
让我们，帮我们的朋友快…
...soon!
回去！
It worked!
起作用了！
I haven't been on a trip like that since college!
自从大学后我就再也没经历过那种旅程了
Donkey?
驴子？
What? Is something in my teeth?
什么？我牙齿里有什么东西吗？
Oh, no! I've been abracadabra-ed into a Fancy Feastin', second-rate sidekick!
哦，不！我被咒语弄成了那个二流伙伴了
At least you don't look like some kind of bloated pinata!
至少你看起来不像是某种臃肿的玩偶
You should think about going on a diet!
你该考虑一下减肥！
You should get yourself a pair of pants. I feel all exposed and nasty!
你该给自己弄条内裤 我感觉全都暴露了，很下流！
So you two think this is funny?
你们两个认为这很有趣吗？
I'm really sorry, guys.
我真的抱歉，伙计们
Don't be. You got us back, kid.
没关系，你把我们弄回来了，孩子
How in the Hans Ohristian Andersen
在安徒生童话里…
am I supposed to parade around in these goofy boots?
我也是该穿着这笨重的靴子到处走吗？
Hey, hey, hey! Be very careful with those.
嘿，嘿，嘿！小心
They were made in Madrid by the finest...
他们出自马德里最好的…
You'll learn to control that.
你会学会怎么控制这个的
Seriously. Ow! You need some comfort inserts or arch supports or something.
真的，哦！你需要些安慰或是支持
Watch it. I'm walking here and I'm gonna keep going until...
小心，我走在这儿 并且将一直走下去直到…
Pinocchio!
匹诺曹！
Shrek! Help me!
史莱克！救我！
- What happened? - Oharming and the villains took over!
- 发生什么事了？ - 查明和那些恶棍占领了这里！
Fiona and the Princesses got away. Now she's...
菲奥娜和公主们走了 现在她…
She's what?! What?!
她怎么了？怎么了？！
Puss! Loan me five bucks.
小猫，借我5块硬币
You heard him. Help the brother out.
你听到了，帮他出来
Do you see any pockets on me?
你看到我身上有口袋吗？
Hold on a second.
等等
I had no idea, really. I... I swear.
我没办法，真的，我…我保证
Quick! Where is Fiona?
快！菲奥娜在哪里？
Oharming has her locked away someplace. You have to find him!
查明把她关在了什么地方 你必须找到他！
He's probably getting ready for the show!
他可能正在准备演出！
Wait, Pinocchio! What show?
等等，匹诺曹！什么演出？
"It's a Happily Ever After After All".
“从此以后过着幸福快乐的生活”
"Shrek's final performance"?
“史莱克的最后演出”？
Shrek! You didn't tell us you were in a play!
史莱克！你没告诉我们你会在演出里出现
I guess I've been so busy I forgot to mention it.
我想我真是太忙了，忘了提到了
The ogre! Get him!
是那个怪物！抓住他！
Don't worry, jefe. I got this.
别担心，老大，我来
Uck! Kill it!
杀了他！
Look. Don't you know who he thinks he is? How dare you!
听着，难道你们不知道他是谁吗？ 你们怎么敢！
We're dealing with amateurs.
真是些土人
He's a star, people! Hello? I'm so sorry about this, Mr. Shrek.
他是个明星，朋友们！哈罗？ 我很抱歉，史莱克先生
I'm going to lose it!
我要生气了！
Is everything ready? You did get the list for the dressing room?
都准备好了吗？你得到更衣室的名单了吗？
Breakfast croissant stuffed with seared sashimi tuna.
早餐是塞有生切金枪鱼片的牛角面包
And I hope you have the saffron corn with jalapeno honey butter.
我希望你吃带有蜂蜜黄油的谷物
Our client cannot get into his proper emotional state
我们的名人没有蜂蜜黄油的话…
withoutjalapeno honey butter!
会达不到好的状态
I just lost it.
我生气了
They should talk to Nancy in Human Resources.
他们该和人力的南希谈谈
Oh, we will have much to say to Nancy, I promise!
哦，我保证我们有很多话要告诉南希
"With this sword, I do...", No! "With..."
“用这把剑，我…”，不
"With this sword, I do smote thee!"
“用这把剑，我将击倒你！”
Is "smote" the right word? "Smoot"?
“击倒”这个词对吗？“击到”？
I don't think that's a word.
我不认为有这个词
Maybe I should just "smite" him. Let's try this again. Now...
也许我该“击倒”他，我们再试一下
Shrek attacks me. I pretend to be afraid.
史莱克攻击我，我假装害怕
"Now the kingdom will get the happily ever after they deserve. Die, ogre!"
“现在这个国家将从此得到他们应得的幸福 去死吧，怪物！”
Blah, blah, blah. Oh, itjust doesn't feel real enough!
哦，感觉不够真实！
Who told you to stop dancing?!
谁要求你停止跳舞？！
Wink and turn.
眨眼，转圈
What are you laying around for? Get up! Honestly!
你躺在那里干吗？起来！老实点！
Our happily ever after is nearly complete, Mummy.
我们从此以后的幸福就要实现了，妈咪
And I assure you...
我向你保证…
...the people of this kingdom will pay dearly for every second...
这个国家的每个人会为 我们等待的每一秒…
...we've had to wait.
付出代价
Break a leg.
断腿
On second thought, let me break it for you.
再想想，还是我来弄断你条腿吧
Thank goodness. I was afraid you wouldn't get back in time.
谢天谢地，我还以为你不会及时回来了呢
Where's Fiona?
菲奥娜在哪里？
Don't worry. She and the others are safe... for now.
不要担心，她和其他的人都很安全
Let me guess. Arthur.
我猜猜，亚瑟
It's Artie, actually.
事实上是叫亚蒂
This boy is supposed to be the new King of Far Far Away?
这孩子就是遥远国的新国王？
How pathetic.
多悲哀啊
Stand still, so I won't make a mess.
不要动，我才不会手发抖
Oharming, stop! I'm here now. You got what you wanted.
查明，住手！我在这里 你得到了你想要的
This isn't about him.
这和他没关系
Then who's it about? I'm supposed to be king, right?
那和谁有关？ 我才应该是国王，对吗？
You weren't really next in line for the throne.
你其实不是下一任王座的继承人
I was.
我才是
But you said the King asked for me personally.
但你说过国王亲自点名要我继任
Not exactly.
不完全正确
What does that mean?
那是什么意思？
I said whatever I had to say, all right?
该说的我都说了，好了吗？
I wasn't right for the job, so I needed some fool to replace me.
我不适合这个位置 因此需要某个傻瓜来代替我
And you fit the bill. So just go!
而你正好合适，你走吧！
You were playing me the whole time.
原来你一直在耍我
You catch on real fast, kid.
你理解的很快，孩子
Maybe you're not as big of a loser as I thought.
也许你不是我想像中的那么失败
You know, for a minute...
你知道，曾经一度…
- I actually thought... - What?
- 我真的以为… - 什么？
That he cared about you? He's an ogre.
他在意你？他是个怪物
What did you expect?
你期盼什么呢？
You really do have a way with children, Shrek.
对付孩子你可真有一套啊，史莱克
∮ Leave me out with the waste ∮
∮ 把我和废物放在外面 ∮
∮ This is not what I do ∮
∮ 这不是我做的 ∮
∮ It's the wrong time ∮
∮ 时间不对 ∮
∮ She's pulling me through ∮
∮ 她在帮我渡过难关 ∮
∮ It's a small crime ∮
∮ 这是个小犯罪 ∮
∮ And I got no excuse ∮
∮ 我没有借口 ∮
∮ And is that all right, yeah? ∮
∮ 这样行吗？ ∮
∮ Is that all right with you? ∮
∮ 你觉得可以吗？ ∮
∮ Is that all right, yeah? ∮
∮ 可以吗？ ∮
∮ If I give my gun away when it's loaded? ∮
∮ 如果上膛后我把枪给别人？ ∮
∮ If you don't shoot it how am I supposed to hold it? ∮
∮ 如果你不开枪，我怎么拿着它？ ∮
∮ Is that all right? Is that all right? ∮
∮ 可以吗？这样行吗？ ∮
∮ Is that all right with you? ∮
∮ 你同意吗？ ∮
∮ No ∮
∮ 不！ ∮
Had we stayed put like I suggested,
要是我们像我说的呆在原处不动
we'd be sipping tea out of little heart-shaped cups.
我们现在就正拿着心形杯喝茶呢
Yeah, heart-shaped cups.
是啊，是啊，心形杯
And eating crumpets smothered with loganberries.
吃着带罗甘莓的煎饼
Yeah, loganberries.
是啊，罗甘莓
- Shut up, Oindy. - Yeah, shut up.
- 闭嘴，辛迪 - 是啊，闭嘴
- No, you shut up. - Stay out of this.
- 不，你闭嘴 - 少管闲事
Who cares who's "running the kingdom"?
谁在乎谁来掌管国家？
- I care. - You should all care.
- 我关心 - 你们都该关心
I have your badge number, tin can!
我记住你们的徽章编号了，铁罐！
- Donkey? - Princess!
- 驴子？ - 公主！
Puss?
猫咪？
I am Puss, stuck here inside this hideous body.
我才是猫咪，粘在了这个丑恶的身体里
And I'm me!
我才是我！
But you're...
但你是…
Everything's fruity in the loops, but what happened is
一切都糟透了，事情是这样的
we went to high school, the boat crashed
我们去了中学，船撞毁了
and we got bippity-boppity-booped by the magic man.
然后我们一个魔法师施了魔法
You poor sweet things.
可怜的家伙
I don't get it.
我没明白
The cat turned into a little horse that smells like feet. What's to get?
这只猫变成了闻起来像臭脚的驴子 什么不明白的？
Who dat?
谁死了？
Where's Shrek?
史莱克呢？
Oharming has him. He plans to kill Shrek tonight in front of the whole kingdom!
查明抓住了他，他计划 今晚在整个国家面前杀了他
All right, everyone. We need to find a way out now.
好了，各位，我们需要找到条出去的路
You're right. Ladies, assume the position!
你说的对，女士们，各就各位
What are you doing?
你们在干吗？
Waiting to be rescued.
等着被救
You've got to be kidding me.
你在开什么玩笑
What else can we do? We're just four...
我们还能怎么做呢？我们只是四个…
...I mean three, super-hot princesses...
我是说三个漂亮的公主
...two circus freaks, a pregnant ogre and an old lady!
两个马戏团小丑，一个怀孕的怪物 还有个老太婆
Excuse me. Old lady coming through.
不好意思，老太婆要爆发了
Mom!
妈妈！
You didn't think you got your fighting skills from your father, did you?
你认为你没有从你父亲那里 学到了战斗技巧，是吗？
Excuse me. There's still one more.
不好意思，我想那还有一面墙
Why don't you just lie down?
你先躺下休息一下吧
Okay, girls, from here on out...
好了，女士们，从这里出去
...we take care of business ourselves.
我们自己管好自己
The Far Far Away Theatre at the Charming Pavilion is proud to present...
先生们女士们，查明阁下的 遥远国剧场将隆重呈现…
..."It's A Happily Ever After After AII."
“从此以后过着幸福快乐的生活”
Enjoy your evening of theatrical reverie, citizen.
市民们，享受这梦幻般的夜晚
Oi! No food or beverages in the theater!
剧场里不允许吃零食和饮料
Places, everyone!
各就各位！
Easy!
轻点！
Sorry. I was showing off for the little one.
对不起，我想跟小家伙炫耀一下
It's Bring Your Kids to Work Day. Oome here, beautiful.
带了孩子来上班，过来，美女
Well, she's got your eye.
她继承了你的眼睛
Who would have thought a monster like me deserved something as special as you?
谁会想到像我这种怪物 能拥有像你一样特别的东西呢
∮ Little birdies, take wing ∮
∮ 小鸟，飞翔 ∮
∮ Flitting down from the trees they appear ∮
∮ 从它们出现的树上飞下来 ∮
∮ And to chirp in my ear ∮
∮ 在我耳边唧唧喳喳 ∮
∮ All because I sing ∮
∮ 都是因为我唱歌 ∮
Move it! Go!
冲啊！冲！
My babies!
我的孩子们！
Help!
救命！
Hey, how's it goin'?
嘿，怎么样？
O to the K. The coast is clear.
O到K，危险已经全部清除
Let's do this. Go, Team Dynamite!
我们行动吧，出去，摧毁小队
I thought we agreed to use the name Team Super Oool.
我认为我们已经同意了 使用超级无敌酷这个小队名字
I recall it was Team Awesome.
我记得是叫帅气小队
I voted for Team Alpha Wolf Squadron.
我投票选了阿尔法狼中队
Okay! From henceforth,
好了，好了！从此以后
we will be Team Alpha Super Awesome Oool Dynamite Wolf Squadron.
我们就是阿尔法超级帅气无敌摧毁狼中队
Ach de liebe! There is some strange little girl over there staring at us!
那边有个奇怪的陌生小女孩盯着我们看
Artie!
亚蒂！
Wait, wait!
等等，等等！
Where is the fire, senor?
你的怒火呢，先生？
Please. Don't act so innocent.
拜托，别装的那么无辜
You both knew what was going on and kept it to yourselves.
你从一开始就知道怎么回事 却一直没说
It's not like it seems.
事情并不是那样的
It's not? I think it seems pretty clear.
不是那样？我认为已经很清楚了
He was using me. That's all.
他在利用我，就是那么回事
Using you? You really don't get it.
利用你？你真的没明白
Shrek only said those things to protect you.
史莱克是为了保护你才这么说的
Oharming was going to kill you, Artie! Shrek saved your life.
不然查明会杀了你的，亚蒂！ 史莱克救了你的命
Oue the spot!
灯光对准！
I wait alone up here
我孤独在这儿等待
I'm trapped another day
被关了又一天
Locked up here, please set me free
被锁在这里，请让我出去
My new life I almost see
我的新生活我快看见
A castle, you and me
一个城堡，你和我
Yes, a castle, you and me
是的，一个城堡，你和我
Oherubs!
天使！
Tis I, Tis I Upon my regal steed
是的，我在我的帝王战马上
Princess, my love
公主，我的爱
At last you shall be freed I'm strong
最终你会自由的 我很强壮
And brave And dashing my way there
很勇敢，正赶来救你
With speed! With might! With soft and bouncy hair!
用我的速度！用我的力量！ 用我那柔软有弹性的头发！
- Through the blistering desert - Hot!
- 穿过恶劣的沙漠 - 炎热！
- Across the stormiest sea - Wet!
- 渡过狂暴的大海 - 潮湿！
Facing creatures so vile
面对如此恶劣的生物
Foul!
恶心！
So you can gaze upon me!
这样你就有机会注视着我
I knew you'd come for me
我知道你会来救我
And now we finally meet
现在我们终于见面了
I knew you'd wait
我知道你会等
And from my plate of love you'd eat
会接受我的爱
Who is this terribly ugly fiend Who so rudely intervened?
这个丑陋的魔鬼是谁？ 谁敢如此粗鲁的来干涉？
Will Charming fight or flee?
查明会战斗还是逃跑？
Please rescue me!
请救我！
From this monstrosity!
救我离开这个怪物！
Fear thee not, honey lamb! I will slice this thing up like a ham!
你别怕，亲爱的！ 我会把这怪物切成肉片
Oh, boy.
哦，孩子
You are about to enter a world of pain
你将进入一个你…
With which you are not familiar!
从未感受过的痛苦世界
It can't be any more painful than your lousy performance.
没有比你的拙劣表演更痛苦的了
"Prepare, foul beast."
“受死吧，恶心的怪物”
Prepare, foul beast, your time is done!
受死吧，恶心的怪物，你的死期已到
Oould you kill me and then sing?
你能不能先杀了我然后再唱？
Be quiet!
安静！
I'm just having fun with you. That's actually a very nice leotard.
我只是和你开玩笑 那真是个漂亮的连衣裤
Thank you.
谢谢
Do they come in men's sizes?
是照男人的尺寸来做的吗？
Now that be funny!
真好笑啊
Enough!
够了！
Now you'll finally know what it's like...
现在你终于知道…
...to have everything you worked for...
对你来说宝贵的东西被夺走…
...everything that's precious to you, taken away.
是一种什么感觉了
Now you'll know how I felt.
现在你会知道我是什么感觉
Sausage roll!
香肠卷
Pray for mercy from Puss!
祈求猫咪的仁慈吧！
And Donkey!
还有驴子！
（字母D）
Hi, honey.
嗨，亲爱的
Sorry we're late. You okay?
对不起，我们来晚了，你还好吗？
Much better, now that you're here.
你在这里好多了
So, Oharming, you want to let me out of these so we can settle this ogre-to-man?
那么，查明，你想放开我 让我们进行真正的怪物对男人的决斗吗？
Ooh, that sounds fun. But I have a better idea.
哦，那听上去很有趣 但我有个更好的主意
No! Let go of me!
不！放开我！
You will not ruin things this time, ogre. Kill it.
这次不会让你毁了一切的，怪物 杀了他
Everybody, stop!
大家，住手！
Oh, what is it now?!
哦，又是什么？！
Artie?
亚蒂？
Who thinks we need to settle things this way?
谁说我们必须要以这种方式解决问题？
You mean you want to be villains your whole lives?
你们想一生都做恶棍吗？
But we are villains! It's the only thing we know.
但我们就是恶棍！ 这是我们唯一所明白的
You never wish you could be something else?
你从没希望做别的什么吗？
Easy for you to say. You're not some evil enchanted tree.
你说的容易，你又不是给施了魔法的树
You morons! Don't listen to him! Attack!
你个蠢人！别听他的！攻击！
What Steve means is it's hard to come by honest work
斯蒂夫的意思是如果全世界都讨厌你
when the whole world's against you.
那么很难得到好工作
Right. Thanks, Ed.
对的，谢谢，爱德
Fair enough. You're right. I'm not a talking tree.
很公平，你说的对 我不是棵会说话的树
But you know...
但你要知道…
...a good friend once told me...
一个好朋友曾经告诉我…
...just because people treat you like a villain, or an ogre...
别人对待你像对待恶棍…
...orjust some loser...
或是怪物，或者像对待一个失败者
...doesn't mean you are one.
这并不意味你就是
What matters most is what you think of yourself.
最重要的是你自己怎么看你自己
If there's something you really want, or someone you want to be...
如果有什么你真的想要的 或是你想成为的…
...the only person standing in your way is you.
唯一能阻拦你的就是你自己
- Me? - Get him!
- 我自己？ - 抓住他！
No, no, no!
不，不，不！
What I mean is each of you...
我的意思是你们每个人…
...is standing in your own way.
都有自己的路
I always wanted to play the flute.
我一直想演奏长笛
I'd like to open up a spa... in France!
我想要在法国开个温泉浴场
I grow daffodils. And they're beautiful.
我想种水仙花，很漂亮的
A new era finally begins!
一个新的时代终于来临了！
Now all of you...
现在你们…
...bow before your King!
向你们的国王鞠躬！
You need to work on your aim.
你需要练习一下瞄准
This was supposed to be my happily ever after!
这本该是我的幸福生活！
Well, you need to keep looking...
那我想你需要继续寻找了…
...because I'm not giving up mine.
因为我不会放弃我的幸福生活
Mommy?
妈咪？
It's yours if you want it.
如果你想要就给你了
But this time it's your choice.
但这次你自己选择
Author!
亚瑟！
Artie! Artie! Artie! Artie!
亚蒂！亚蒂！亚蒂！
Excuse me. That's my seat.
不好意思，那是我的座位
Okay, Senor Hocusy-Pocusy, the time has come to rectify some wrongs!
好了，大魔法师先生 现在是时候纠正错误了！
Though I have been enjoying these cat baths.
尽管我很享受猫的沐浴
Please say you didn't.
请说你不喜欢
All right! Look.
好的！听着
You'll feel a pinch and possibly lower intestinal discomfort...
你们可能会感到被掐了一下 也许还会肠子不舒服
...but this should do the trick.
但这应该有效
- Are you? - I'm me again!
- 是你吗？ - 我又变回我自己啦！
- And I am not you! - All right!
- 我不再是你啦！ - 好啦！
Oops.
唉
Ah, never mind.
啊，没关系
What did I tell you? The kid's going to be a great king.
我怎么告诉你的？ 这孩子会成为一个伟大的国王
Well, for what it's worth, you would have, too.
确实，你本来也会是的
I have something much more important in mind.
我心里还有更重要的事情
Finally.
最终
Dada.
爸爸
∮ Was I wrong about the world? It's a beautiful new place ∮
∮ 我对世界的看法错了吗？这是一个美丽的新地方 ∮
I smell Shrek Junior!
嘿嘿，我闻到了小史莱克的味道！
∮ Where else could a creep like me ∮
∮ 还有什么地方能像我这样的怪物 ∮
∮ Meet such a pretty face ∮
∮ 遇到这么一张漂亮的脸 ∮
∮ Meeting every day with the rising sun ∮
∮ 每天与日出相遇 ∮
∮ Looking up, it's looking like... ∮
∮ 抬头看，就像... ∮
∮ My losing streak is done ∮
∮ 我的连胜结束了 ∮
∮ Peek-a-boo! ∮
∮ 藏猫猫 ∮
A bouncy, bouncy, boy!
跳啊，跳，宝贝
∮ Used to always feel like ∮
∮ 以前总觉得 ∮
∮ Wished that I was dressed better ∮
∮ 希望我穿得更好 ∮
Where's the baby?
婴儿在哪里？
∮ Never had a lot of luck Until I finally met her ∮
∮ 直到最后遇到她，我才有很多运气 ∮
∮ Meeting every day with the rising sun ∮
∮ 每天与日出相遇 ∮
∮ Looking up, it's looking like... ∮
∮ 抬头看，就像 ∮
∮ My losing streak is done ∮
∮ 我的连胜结束了 ∮
Well... what shall we do now?
那…我们现在该干吗呢？
I got it.
我来吧
∮ Puss and Donkey, baby! Once again, come on ∮
∮ 猫和驴，宝贝！再来一次，加油 ∮
∮ I want to thank you for letting me be myself ∮
∮ 谢谢你让我做我自己 ∮
∮ Again ∮
∮ 又来了 ∮
∮ Look at my hips ∮
∮ 看看我的臀部！ ∮
∮ I want to thank you for letting me be myself ∮
∮ 谢谢你让我做我自己 ∮
∮ Again ∮
∮ 又来了 ∮
- ∮ Break it down ∮ - ∮ Let's go ∮
- ∮ 分解它 ∮  - ∮ 我们走 ∮
∮ Stiff all in the collar ∮
∮ 笔挺都在衣领里 ∮
∮ Fluffy in the face ∮
∮ 毛茸茸的脸 ∮
∮ Chit chat chatter trying ∮
∮ 闲聊 ∮
∮ Stuffy in the place ∮
∮ 闷闷不乐 ∮
∮ Thank you for the par-tay ∮
∮ 谢谢你的宴会 ∮
∮ But I could never stay ∮
∮ 但我不能留下来 ∮
∮ I'm sorry ∮
∮ 对不起 ∮
∮ I got many things on my mind ∮
∮ 我脑子里有很多事情 ∮
∮ But the word's in the way ∮
∮ 但是这个词挡住了路 ∮
∮ And I want to thank you for letting me be myself ∮
∮ 谢谢你让我做我自己 ∮
∮ Again ∮
∮ 又来了！ ∮
∮ Different strokes for different folks ∮
∮ 不同的人有不同的笔画 ∮
∮ Thank you for letting me be myself ∮
∮ 谢谢你让我做我自己 ∮
∮ Again ∮
∮ 再说一遍 ∮
∮ Break it down ∮
∮ 分解它！ ∮
∮ Puss and Donkey, baby! Puss and Donkey, baby! ∮
∮ 猫和驴，宝贝！猫和驴，宝贝！ ∮
∮ Puss and Donkey, baby! ∮
∮ 猫和驴，宝贝！ ∮
∮ Dance to the music ∮
∮ 跟着音乐跳舞 ∮
∮ All night long ∮
∮ 通宵 ∮
∮ Everyday people ∮
∮ 普通人 ∮
∮ Sing a simple song ∮
∮ 唱一首简单的歌 ∮
∮ Mama's so happy ∮
∮ 妈妈太高兴了 ∮
∮ Mama start to cry ∮
∮ 妈妈开始哭了 ∮
∮ Papa's still singing ∮
∮ 爸爸还在唱歌 ∮
∮ You can make it if you try So try ∮
∮ 你能做到，如果你努力，那么努力！ ∮
∮ Thank you for letting me be myself ∮
∮ 谢谢你让我做我自己 ∮
∮ Again ∮
∮ 又来了！ ∮
∮ Thank you for letting me be myself ∮
∮ 谢谢你让我做我自己 ∮
∮ Again ∮
∮ 又来了！ ∮
∮ Oome on, Donkey. Do something right ∮
∮ 噢，驴子，做正确的事！ ∮
∮ Put the hoofs together! Put the hoofs together! ∮
∮ 把蹄子放在一起！把蹄子放在一起！ ∮
∮ Stomp your boots, baby! Stomp your boots, baby! Stomp your boots, baby! ∮
∮ 跺你的靴子，宝贝！踩你的靴子，宝贝！踩你的靴子，宝贝！ ∮
∮ Thank you for letting me be myself ∮
∮ 谢谢你让我做我自己 ∮
∮ Again ∮
∮ 又来了！ ∮
∮ I want to thank you for letting me be myself ∮
∮ 谢谢你让我做我自己 ∮
∮ Again ∮
∮ 又来了！ ∮
∮ Thank you, thank you, thank you ∮
∮ 谢谢，谢谢，谢谢 ∮
∮ Want to thank you Just to be my ∮
∮ 想谢谢你做我的朋友 ∮
∮ Because I just want to be my... See? ∮
∮ 因为我只想成为我的... 看到了吗？ ∮
∮ Can I, can I thank you! Can I ∮
∮ 我能，我能谢谢你吗！我可以吗 ∮
∮ Yes! Yes! ∮
∮ 是的！对！ ∮